Wow. That ripped.
它会扯破衣服
That ripped real nice!
一点也不含糊
How many times do I have to tell you? You turn and slide.
你要我说几次？要侧身滑出来
Turn and slide.
侧身滑出来
You don't turn and slide.
不是侧身滑出来
You throw it out!
是把它扔出去
I get tetanus shots every time I get dressed!
我每次穿衣服 都得打破伤风预防针
We're not throwing it out. I built it with my own hands!
不能扔掉，这是我亲手钉的
How about we sell it?
好，那卖掉呢？
All right.
好吧
But you'll have to tell them.
不过你得告诉它们
Can we stick you in another cabinet? They seem all right with it!
你们可以搬个家吗？ 看来它们没意见
The One with the Cat
本集播出：“灵猫”
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
Hey,why did the chicken fall out of the tree?
鸡为什么不会从树下掉下来？
Why?
为什么？
Because you have doody on your head.
因为头上有翅膀
Yeah,it was funnier when Ben told it.
班说就很好笑
Hey,Monica. It's Chip.
摩妮卡，我是奇普 漂亮！
Who's Chip?
谁是奇普？
It was good running into you today.
很高兴今天遇见你
My number is 555-9323. Give me a call.
我的电话是5559323 打给我，就这样
"Chip" is Chip Matthews.
奇普就是奇普马修斯
The guy who took Rachel to the prom? Why's he calling you?
瑞秋的高中舞会舞伴？ 他打给你干什么？
Because I ran into him at the bank. He is still so cute.
我在银行遇见他，他还是好帅
You're so lucky! He's like the most popular guy in school!
你好幸运 他是全校最红的男生
I know!
我知道
Chip? Hi,it's Monica.
奇普？我是摩妮卡
好…好
好
Oh,my God! We just had the best conversation!
好，再见 天哪，我们聊得好愉快
I was just leaving.
我正要走
Good.
好
I've got a report to read.
我要看报告
It's eight pages. I hope I don't fall asleep.
有八页，但愿我不会睡着
Why? Did you write it?
为什么？是你写的？
Look at that!
你看看
Chip Matthews called. I wonder what he wants.
奇普马修斯打电话来 不晓得有什么事
Well,actually....
其实…
I bet he sensed that I was ready to have sex with another guy.
他一定感应到 我可以跟别的男人上床了
Why don't you give him a call?
那你何不打给他？
好啊
-Are you sure you want to hear this? -I'm sure.
你真的想听？ 真的
Chip! Hi,it's Rachel.
奇普，我是瑞秋
Rachel Greene.
瑞秋葛林
You left me a message?
你留言给我？
Yes,you did. My roommate wrote it down.
你有，我的室友记下来了
Monica Geller?
摩妮卡盖勒？
Oh,that's right!
原来如此
He called to ask out Monica.
他是要约摩妮卡
That's got to be embarrassing.
真是尴尬
Dumb drunken bitch
醉醺醺的白痴贱人
Thank you!
谢谢
Here's a question.
请问一下
Where'd you get the "finest oak east of the Mississippi"?
密西西比以东 最好的橡木家具在哪里？
First tell us where you got the prettiest lace in the land.
你先说 全国最漂亮的蕾丝在哪里
It's your ad.
这是你们的广告
Looks good?
不赖吧？
"Stunning entertainment center,fine
“高级视听娱乐柜，精致…”
Fine ltalian craftsmanship."
“精致意大利手工”
You're selling the entertainment center?
天哪，你们要卖娱乐柜？
Why? I love it.
为什么？我喜欢那个柜子
-You want it? -No.
你们要吗？ 不要
Gepetto?
“名家手艺”？
Five thousand dollars?
“定价5千”？
Are you insane?
你疯了吗？
The ad alone cost $300.
登广告就要3百
I'm changing it to $50 or your best offer.
我要改成50元或再议
What kind of profit is that? And you call yourself an accountant?
那有什么利润可言？ 你也配当会计师？
我不是
What do you do?
那你是什么？
I can't believe you don't know.
你居然不知道我干哪一行
I actually don't know.
我也不知道 是不是什么…
Oh,my God,no! Shoo,kitty!
天哪，不要，走开 不要…
There's a kitty in my guitar case.
阿甘，我的吉他盒里有一只猫
Everyone's gonna want one.
嘘…其他人都想要
Come on,you!
给我过来
Crazy!
真是的
-Oh,my God! -What?
天哪 什么？
Nothing.
没事
What's wrong?
怎么了？
I just have this really strong feeling that this cat is my mother.
我只是有一股强烈的感觉 这只猫是我妈
The mom you met in Montauk? She was a cat?
莫陶克那个妈妈？ 她是一只猫？
That makes the fact that she owns beach-front property all the more impressive.
而她居然拥有滨海小屋
No. She was a human lady.
不，她是一个人
This is the spirit of my mom,Lilly. The one that killed herself.
这是莉莉妈妈的灵魂 自杀的那个
Have you been taking your grandmother's glaucoma medicine again?
是她变成一只猫 还是你又偷吃外婆的青光眼药
No,Dr. Skeptismo.
没有，疑心病博士
I'm sure. First of all,there's the feeling.
我很肯定 第一，我有这个感觉
And for another, she went into my guitar case...
还有，她跑进我的吉他盒里
...which is lined with orange felt.
它的衬里是橘色的
My mother's favorite fish was orange roughy.
我妈最喜欢的鱼是橘棘鲷
Cats like fish.
猫喜欢吃鱼
You had me with orange felt.
听到橘色衬里我就信了
Hi,Mommy!
妈
I haven't seen this smile in 17 years.
我17年没看到这个笑容了
-Phoebe's mom's got a huge pair of -Let it go!
菲比的妈有两颗好大的… 算了吧
When were you going to tell me that you're dating Chip?
你什么时候要告诉我 你要跟奇普约会？
Now?
现在？
Can I go out with him?
我跟他约会没关系吧？
No. I can't believe you'd want to after what he did to me.
当然有关系 他那样对我耶
That thing at the prom?
你是说舞会的事？
I couldn't find him for hours! He was having sex with Amy Welsh!
摩妮卡，我2个小时找不到他 他跑去跟艾美威许做爱
That was in high school. How can it still bother you?
那是高中的事 你怎么还会在意？
Oh,yeah,you're right,Moni-cow.
说得也是，莫母猪
Okay,I hear you.
我懂了
Why do you have to go out with Chip?
你为什么偏要跟奇普约会？
We went to different schools.
我们的高中不一样
We went to the same school.
少来，我们上同一所高中
You went to one where you were popular.
你在高中是风云人物
You rode on Chip's motorcycle and wore his letterman jacket.
你坐奇普的摩托车 穿他的特优选手外套
I went to one where I wore a band uniform that was specially made.
我穿的是特制的乐队制服
They had that specially made?
那是特制的？
It was a Home Ec project.
那是家政课的作业之一
Oh,my God! They said it was for the mascot.
天哪 他们说那是给吉祥物穿的
Back then I thought that I'd never get to go out with a Chip Matthews.
那时候我以为 我永远不可能跟奇普约会
Now he's called me up and asked me out.
现在他打来约我
The fat girl inside me really wants to go. I owe her this.
我心中那个胖女孩真的很想去 这是我欠她的
I never let her eat.
我从不让她尽情的吃
-You go out with him. -Really?
你去吧 真的？
If possible,could you leave him and have sex with another guy?
如果可以，你能不能丢下他 去跟别人做爱？
I'll try.
我试试看
Any luck getting rid of the entertainment center?
娱乐柜卖得怎样？
There were a couple calls, but they won't work out.
昨晚有几通询问电话 但我都觉得不可行
Joey has a very careful screening process.
乔伊有一套严格的筛选过程
Not everyone is qualified to own wood and nails.
并非每个人都适合拥有木制品
Stop it!
别挣扎了
She keeps trying to get away. Just like when she was alive.
她一直想跑走 跟在世时一样
How long is your mom going to be with us?
你妈要跟我们在一起多久？
I'm not sure.
我不确定
I guess until she gets used to the fact that there's...
直到她能接受我有了…
...a new mom.
新妈妈吧
Now she's worried that she'll be replaced.
她很担心会被取代
That's not going to happen,is it?
才不会呢，对不对？
I have to go make a call.
我去房里回个电话
Why not use this phone?
怎么不在这里打？
I'm returning a call from a certain mom at the B-E-A-C-H.
我要打给住在（海边）的妈妈
I just spelled the wrong word.
我说反了
Anyway,I don't want to do it in front of someone with a tail.
我不想在有尾巴的人面前打
Hey,you swore you would never tell.
你发誓不说的
So am I crazy,or does Phoebe's mom remind anyone else of a cat?
是我疯了，还是有人也觉得 菲比的妈像一只猫？
Ross,don't start.
罗斯，别提了 拜托
You actually believe there's a woman inside that cat?
你们真的相信 那只猫是一个女人变的？
I believe it.
我相信
No,you don't.
你才不信
Yes,I do.
我信
No,you
你才不…
You know what?
你知道吗？
You won't suck me into this.
我不会跟你争辩
Sure I will. Because you always have to be right.
你会 你总是要说服别人
I do not always have Okay,okay.
我才没有… 好
Jurassic Park could happen.
“侏罗纪公园”是有可能的
And you know what? Actually, I do think Kirk was smarter than Spock.
还有 我觉得蟑螂比恐龙聪明
You were kidding about the Kirk-Spock-thing,though,right?
刚才那句是开玩笑吧？
That's pretty nice.
还不赖嘛
"Pretty nice"?
还不赖？
Pardon my roommate. He wanted to marry this.
原谅我的室友 他简直想娶它过门
We don't have $50. But would you trade for it?
我们没有50块钱 你们愿意交换吗？
We got a canoe.
我们有一艘独木舟
I don't think we need a canoe.
我们不需要独木舟
You got to take it.
你们一定要收下独木舟
Just take the entertainment center.
你们就把柜子搬走吧
Then when you get home, throw the canoe away.
等你们到家，再把独木舟扔掉
We're not throwing it away. I built it.
想都别想，那是我亲手造的
Good for you!
干得好！
（中央咖啡馆）
You won't believe what I found on a telephone pole.
你们看我在电线杆上发现什么
Look familiar?
眼熟吗？
Apparently Phoebe's mother also goes by the name "Julio."
显然菲比的母亲也叫胡立欧
Wait a minute. This is not the same cat. This cat's only this big.
不一样吧，这只只有这么大
A little girl's looking for this cat. Know what that means?
有个小女孩在找这只猫 知道这代表什么吗？
Yeah! $200 reward split five ways!
知道，五个人平分2百元赏金
Do we have to tell her?
要告诉她吗？
-Yes,we do. -But it's made her so happy.
当然要告诉她 但她现在好开心
Little girl misses her cat.
想念猫咪的小女孩
Crazy lady thinks her mother is in a cat.
觉得猫是母亲转世的疯婆子
I have to go have dinner with my son.
好，我要去跟我儿子吃饭
Can I trust that when you see Phoebe, you will tell her?
你们见到菲比会告诉她吧？
会
Thank you.
谢谢
I hate when Ross is right.
我最讨厌罗斯说对了
He is right,isn't he?
他说得对，对吧？
This might be one time when he's wrong.
搞不好这一次他错了
-You think? -Oh,no. He's right.
是吗？ 不，他说得对
About your mom.
菲比，关于你的母亲… 怎样？
How's that going?
你们处得好吗？
So great. We took a nap together today.
棒呆了，我们今天一起睡午觉
Mom fell asleep on my tummy and purred.
妈在我肚子上睡着还打呼
That's so sweet.
真温馨
I'm gonna get some coffee.
我去点咖啡
What'd you say,Joe? I'll be right there.
乔伊你说什么？我马上过去
I just feel so....
菲比 我觉得好…
-All right! -I'm coming already!
知道了啦 马上来
Not yet,not yet,not yet!
还没还没还没…
-Hello,Chip. -How you doing?
奇普 瑞秋，你好吗？
I'm great!
很好
Got a great job. I have wonderful friends.
我有一份好工作，一群好朋友
Though I'm not seeing anyone now, I've never felt better about myself.
虽然现在没有男朋友 却对自己很满意
So,Monica ready yet?
摩妮卡好了吗？
She'll be out in a second.
她马上就好
So,Chip,how's Amy Welsh?
奇普，艾美威许好吗？
Amy Welsh? I haven't seen her since
艾美威许？我们自从…
So,Monica about ready?
摩妮卡快好了吗？
-Wow,you look great. -Thanks.
你好漂亮 谢谢
-Well,you guys have fun. -Catch you later.
好好去玩吧 再联络
Bye,Chip.
奇普再见
-Are you sure you're okay about this? -Actually
你真的不在意？ 其实…
Okay,great.
太好了
This is the unit for you.
买这个柜子就对了
Sturdy construction, tons of storage.
坚固耐用，容量超大
Some big enough to fit a grown man.
甚至塞得进一个大人
-What? -Yeah,I got in there myself once.
什么？ 对，我就进去过一次
My roommate bet me $5 I couldn't.
我的室友赌5元说我进不去
Then he stuck a board through the handles and locked me in.
然后在门把上塞棍子把我关住
It was funny till I felt like it was a coffin.
起先很好玩，后来感觉像棺材
No,you can't fit in there. It's not deep enough.
你才进不去，它不够深
Oh,yeah?
是吗？
If I can't...
要是我进不去…
...I'll knock $5 off the price.
就少算你5块钱
All right,you have yourself a deal.
就这么说定 好
See? I told you.
你看，我就说吧
Sometimes I come in here just to get away from it.
有时我会进进出出的玩
Hey,a nickel!
有5分钱
Here we are.
到了
You still have the Chipper!
天哪，你的奇车还在
The what?
什么？
That's what we called your motorcycle in high school.
那是你的车子在高中的外号
A motorcycle's a chopper.
摩托车也叫机车
And you're Chip.
而你叫奇普
Never mind.
没事
I think it's cute.
真可爱
A lipper from Chipper.
奇普亲亲
Are you still in touch with anyone?
你还有跟哪些同学联络？
There's Rachel...
有瑞秋，还有…
...and that's it. How about you?
就这样，你呢？
I still hang with Simens and Zana. I see Spindler,Levine,Kelly.
我还在跟西门斯、萨纳混 也常跟史宾、莱文、凯利见面
I run into Goldie...
三不五时会遇见高第
...Stick,Brown,Sulkov,McGuire...
史迪、布朗、苏卡夫、麦奎尔
...J.T.,Beardsley.
杰弟、毕斯利
Is that all?
就这样？
After high school, you kind of lose touch.
毕了业都会失去联络
I ran into Richard Dorfman.
我有遇见李察多夫曼
-How is he? -Me and Simens gave him a wedgie.
他好吗？ 不太好，被我和西门斯敲竹杠
Isn't he an architect?
他不是建筑师吗？
They still wear underwear.
建筑师也要穿内裤
Oh,my God!
天哪！
What?
怎么了？
Are you all right?
你还好吗？ 还好
What happened?
怎么回事？
Oh,man,he promised he wouldn't take the chairs!
他答应不拿沙发椅的
How were you locked in? Where the hell is all of our stuff?
你怎么会被关进去？ 我们的东西呢？
This guy came by to look at the unit...
有一个人来看柜子
...and he said it won't fit a grown man.
他说它塞不下一个大人
So you got in voluntarily?
所以你自愿进去？
I was trying to make a sale!
我想把柜子卖出去
If I ever run into him, you know what I'll do?
要是让我碰上他 你猜我会怎样？
Bend over?
把屁股翘起来？
And then Zana just let one rip!
萨纳干脆让另一个破掉
Not that I don't enjoy talking about high school...
我不是不喜欢回忆往事
...because I do.
我喜欢
Maybe we can talk about something else.
但我们可以聊点别的
I don't know where you work.
像你，我还不晓得你的工作
-You know where I work. -I do?
你知道啊 我知道？
The movie theater. You used to come in all the time.
电影院啊，你以前常来
Still at the Multiplex?
你还在影城做事？
Like I'd give up that job!
我怎么可能换工作
Free popcorn and candy anytime I want?
随时都有爆米花和糖果可吃
I can get you posters.
我可以帮你拿海报
Thanks,I'm set.
谢谢，不用了
Oh,you know who came in the other night? Peters.
你猜那天谁来了？彼得斯
Told me he just went out with Leslie Maskin. Got to third base.
他说他刚才跟女朋友上了三垒
Do you still live with your parents?
你还住在家里？
Yeah,but I can stay out as late as I want.
对，但是没有门禁
You know,with all of our stuff gone, the unit doesn't seem that big.
少了别的东西 柜子就没那么大了
Why couldn't he have been a kidnapper.
那个人怎么不是绑匪？
They really got you guys. Your TV,the chairs.
他们还真是大搬家 电视、沙发椅
Your microwave,the stereo.
微波炉、音响
Man,he took the five of spades!
天哪，他把黑桃5拿走了
No,here it is.
在这里
Oh,my God! What happened?
天哪！怎么了？
Joey was born,and then 28 years later, I was robbed!
乔伊出生 28年后，我被抢了
So how was your date?
怎么样？
Well,I always wanted to go out with Chip in high school.
我高中时一直想跟奇普约会
Tonight,I actually went out with Chip in high school.
今晚 我真的跟高中的奇普约会了
Honey,I'm sorry.
真可惜
Not only did I get to go out with Chip...
不会，我不但跟奇普约了会
...I got to dump Chip.
我还甩了他
-That's so great! -I know.
太棒了 我知道
What did the insurance company say?
保险公司怎么说？
They said,"You don't have insurance. Stop calling us."
他们说 “你们没投保，别再打来了”
You didn't tell her?
你们没有告诉她？
Okay,fine.
好吧
菲比
Listen...
听我说
...this cat belongs to a little girl.
这只猫是一个小女孩的
There are flyers all over the place.
路上帖满了寻猫启事
I'm sorry,sweetie.
对不起
We can take her back with you if you want.
我们可以陪你把猫送回去
But,you know,she chose to find me.
但是她选择来找我
I have to respect her decision,right?
我得尊重她的决定，对吧？
-That's a good call. -That's right.
有道理 没错
Enough is enough.
不对，别再闹了
I'm sorry you feel guilty about spending time with your new mom.
我很遗撼你跟新妈妈在一起 会有罪恶感
But this isn't your old mom.
但这不是你的旧妈妈
This is a cat.
这是一只猫
Julio the cat.
它叫胡立欧
Not Mom! Cat.
不是妈妈，是猫
Ross,how many parents have you lost?
罗斯，你失去过几个父母？
None.
零个
Then you don't know how it feels when one of them comes back.
那你就无法体会 其中一个回来的感觉，对吧？
I believe this is my mother.
我相信这是我的母亲
Even if I'm wrong,who cares?
就算不是又怎样？
Just be a friend,okay? Be supportive.
你就当个好朋友，支持我
I'm sorry.
对不起
Okay.
好
I don't know what to say.
我不知道该说什么
You could say...
你可以...
...you're sorry to her mom.
...向她的妈妈道歉
I think she would like that.
我想她会接受
Come here. Here,come here.
乖，过来
Mrs. Buffay?
布非太太？
Sorry about what I said.
我为我说的话道歉
It was insensitive of me to say...
我实在很伤人
...that you were just a cat...
说你只是一只猫
...when,clearly,you are also...
很显然的，你也是…
...the reincarnated spirit...
我朋友的母亲…
...of my friend's mother.
灵魂转世
Thank you.
谢谢你
We both forgive you.
我们都原谅你
What will you do about the little girl?
那个小女孩怎么办？
Listen.
好，听我说
Mom,I hope you know you still mean a lot to me.
妈，你对我还是很重要
You're welcome to come back anytime.
你随时都可以回来
If she'd come back as a couch, we'd really appreciate it.
要是她可以变成一张沙发 我们会很感激
Come on. I'll take you home.
走吧，我带你回家
-I'll go with you. -Me too.
我跟你去 我也去
I got an extra futon.
我有多的蒲团
Dude,you don't have to brag. We got nothing here.
你拽个屁啊，我们什么都没有
谨此纪念桃乐丝考夫曼
You know....
说真的…
It's peaceful out here.
这里真幽静